Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.11.18 00:03:03
异形续集
[ Electronic Beep ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Thud ]
[ Respirator Hissing ]
生命迹象指数全为绿色
[ Man ] Bio readouts are all in the green.  Looks like she's alive.
看来她还活着
只找到她，各位
Well, there goes  our salvage, guys.
今天觉得如何？
How are we today?  Ohh. Terrible.
糟透了.
Well, better than  yesterday, at least.
至少比昨天好多了
这是那里？
Where am I?  You're safe.
你很安全
你已在基地休息了数天
You're at Gateway Station.  Been here a couple of days.
你有点虚弱，但现在已没事了
You were pretty groggy at first,  but now you're okay.
看来有人来拜访你
Oh, looks like  you've got a visitor.
钟斯，过来
Jonesy. Come here.
过来
Hey, come here.
你好吗？你真是只笨猫
How are you,  you stupid cat?
你去那里了？
How are you?  Where have you been?
我想你们必定已会过面
Guess you two  have met, huh?  I'm Burke. Carter Burke.
卡特巴特，我是公司的人
I work for the company,  but don't let that fool you.  I'm really an okay guy.
别被我骗了，我是好人
真高兴见到你好多了
I'm glad to see you're  feeling a little better.
他们说你的虚脱很快会好
They tell me that all  the weakness and disorientation  should pass soon.
那只是过度长眠的自然影响
That's just natural side effects  of such an unusually long hypersleep,  or something like that.
那是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我漂流了多久？
How long  was I out there?
[ Woman On P.A. ]  Inhalation Therapy, report to-
还没有人跟你说过吗？
Has no one discussed  this with you yet?
没有
No.  But, I mean...
我可真的不认得这地方
I don't... recognize  this place.
我知道，好吧
No, I know. Uh-
你可能会吓一跳，因很久了
Okay. It's just that,  uh, this might be  a shock to you.
多久了？请说
It's long-  How long?
Please.
57年
57 years.  What?
什么？
That's the thing.  You were out there  for 57 years.
你在外面漂流了57年
你被漂流到航道外
What happened was  you had drifted  right through the core systems.
拯救队能找到你已经好运
And it's really  just blind luck...
that a deep-salvage team  found you when they did.
千分之一的机会率
It's one in a thousand,  really.
你能活着真是幸运
I think you're damn lucky  to be alive, kiddo. You could  be floating out there forever.
你可能会永远漂流在外太空
[ Stammering ]  You- You okay?
你还好吧？
- [ Hisses ]  - Uhh-
[ Heart Pounding ]
- [ Hisses ]  - Uuh!
你还好吗？
You okay?
[ Groaning ]
- [ Hisses ]  - Oh-h-h! Oh, God!
老天
护士，快来
Nurse! Please!  God!
Someone get in here now!  [ Screaming ]
Now!
捉住她
- Hold!  - Please.
求求你
Hold on!
捉住她
救救我
Kill me!
不要，不要
No!
[ Gasping ]  Uh!
又做恶梦了？
Bad dreams again?  You want something  to help you sleep?
你需要安眠药吗？
不
No.
我睡够了
[ Sighs ]  I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
钟斯，过来
[ Meows ]  Shh.
没事了，没事了
It's all right.
It's all right now.  [ Purring ]
结束了
It's over.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Chirping Stops ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]  Dr Hirsch, 334. Dr. Hirsch, 334.
抱歉，我迟到了 我整个早上都好忙
Hi. Sorry I'm late.  I've been running behind  all morning.
我的女儿有没有消息？
Is there any word  about my daughter?
Uh... I really think  we should worry  about the hearing now.
我们应该先谈听证会的事
我们时间不多
'Cause we don't have a lot of time, okay?  I read your deposition, and it's great.
我看过你的证供，很不错
你只要坚持你的说法 应该不会有问题的
If you just stick to that,  I think we'll be fine.  The thing to remember is,
会有很多重要人物到场 包括调查局，星际贸易委员会
there're gonna be a lot  of heavyweights in there.
You've got feds  and Interstellar  Commerce Commission,
殖民地行政主管，保险公司… 你有没有我女儿的消息？
Colonial Administration,  insurance company guys-
Do you have any news  about my daughter?
我们的确查到了一些消息
Well, we did come up  with some information.  Why don't we sit down?
坐下来谈吧
我本来想等到审判之后 再告诉你
I was hoping to wait  until after the inquest.
Um-
蕾普莉克伦 应该是夫姓吧？
"Amanda Ripley-McClaren"-  married name, I guess-
66岁，那是她死亡的时间 是两年前的事了
"Age 66."
And that was at  the time of her death,
which was two years ago.
我很遗憾
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
她火葬后埋在威斯康辛 没有子女
She was cremated and interred  at Westlake Repository,  Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.  [ Briefcase Closes ]
[ Inhales Sharply ]
我答应她 她生日的时候会回家
I promised her...  that I'd be home  for her birthday.
陪她过十一岁生日
Her 11th birthday.  [ Choking Up ]
[ Sobbing ]
我们得谈谈拒绝毁弃条例的事
[ Man #1 ]  I'djust like to go, uh-
back to this point about  the override destruct order.
我不懂，我在这儿三个半小时
[ Man #2 ]  Is it in the file?  I don't understand this.
We have been here  for three and a half hours.
同一件事你要我说多少遍？
Now, how many different ways  do you want me to tell  the same story?
你得替公司着想
Look at it from  our perspective,  please.
Please?
你坦白表示引爆船舰
Now, you freely admit to  detonating the engines of,
因此摧毁价值连城的太空船
and thereby destroying,  an M-class starsreighter,
a rather expensive piece  of hardware.
共值四千二百万元
Forty-two million  in adjusted dollars.
这还不包括货物
That's minus payload,  of course.
救生船记录证实你的证供
The lifeboat's flight recorder  corroborates some elements  of your account,
不明原因使船迫降LV426
in that, for reasons unknown,  the Nostromo set down  on LV-426,
该星球不适合生存
an unsurveyed planet at that time,  that it resumed its course...
太空船再度启程后
and was subsequently  set for self-destruct  by you for reasons unknown.
却被你以不明原因自动引爆
不是不明原因，我已经说过
Not for reasons unknown.  I told you.
我们奉公司命令去带回异形
We set down there  on company orders to get this thing,  which destroyed my crew...
它消灭我的队员 和你那艘昂贵的太空船
and your expensive ship.
分析化验小组发现
The analysis team,  which went over the lifeboat  centimeter by centimeter,
被你消灭的东西没有生命迹象
found no physical evidence  of the creature you describe.
很好，因为我把它抛出气舱外
Good!  That's because I blew it  out of the goddamn air lock,
跟我说的一样
like I said.
LV426星球
Are there any species  like this hostile organism  on LV-426?
是否有这种生物存在？
没有，只有岩石，没有生物
No. It's a rock.  No indigenous life.
难道我的智商在长眠时衰退了
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply  while I was away?
我说过，那不是当地的生物
Ma'am, I already said  it was not indigenous.
是外星船，异形不是那儿来的
It was a derelict spacecraft.  It was an alien ship.
It was not from there.  Do you get it?  We homed in on its beacon.
懂吗？我们收到它们的信号
结果找到三百多个报告里 都没有的玩意
And found something  never recorded once...
in over 300 surveyed worlds.
一种活在人体内的怪物
- "A creature that gestates  inside a living human host."  - Yes.
是的
These are your words.  "And has concentrated acid  for blood."
这是你的说法
它的血液有强酸性，对吗？
没错
That's right.
听着，我知道发生什么事
Look. I can see  where this is going,
不过我要说的是怪物的确存在
but I'm telling you  that those things exist.
谢谢，足够了
- Thank you, Officer Ripley.  That will be all.  - Please. You're not listening to me.
拜托，你没听进去 凯恩是我的队员
Kane, the crew member-
他进去看过，有上千个异形的卵
Kane, who went into that ship,  said he saw  thousands of eggs there.
谢谢你，别说了
Thousands.  Thank you.  That will be all.
该死，我还没说完
Goddamn it,  that's not all!
要是有一只侵入 我们就真的完了
Because if one of those things  gets down here,  then that will be all!
你和这些你认为很重要的
Then all of this-  this bullshit that you think  is so important-
废话便真的完了
You can just kiss  all of that good-bye!
本庭判决蕾普莉军官 军籍号码NRC14472
It is the finding  of this court of inquiry that...
Warrant Officer E. Ripley,
NOC14472,
因做出不当判断 所以不适合持有ICC执照
has acted with  questionable judgment...
and is unfit to hold  an I.C.C. license  as a commercial flight officer.
并担任星际飞行官的任务
所以我们将永久吊销其执照
Said license is hereby  suspended indefinitely.
目前将不会以任何罪名起诉你
Now, no criminal charges  will be filed against you  at this time,
不过你将接受 六个月的心理治疗
and you are released  on your own recognizance...
for a six-month period  ofpsychometric probation,
并每个月接受 ICC心理医师的检查
to include monthly review  by an I.C.C. psychiatric technician.
休庭
These proceedings are closed.
“资料封锁”
你应该冷静点
That could have  been better.
听着，蕾普莉
Look, I think the-  Ripley?  Van Leuwen.
你何不查查LV426区
Why don't you  just check out LV-426?
没有这个必要
Because I don't have to.  There have been people there  for over 20 years,
那里有人工作二十年以上 从来没说过有敌人
and they never complained  about any hostile organism.  What do you mean? What people?
什么意思？什么人？
他们去装设大气工程 以便有空气呼吸
Terraformers.  Planet engineers.
They go in, set up these  big atmosphere processors  to make the air breathable.
花了十年的时间
Takes decades.
这就是我们所说的外星殖民地
It's what we call  a "Shake 'N Bake" colony.
有多少人？
How many are there?  How many colonists?
有多少殖民地？
不知道，大概有60到70户
I don't know-  60, maybe 70 families.  Do you mind?
借过
有住户？
Families.
老天
Jesus.
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Low Chattering ]
[ Woman On P.A.,  Indistinct ]
[ Machines Clacking ]
我到下面维修部去
I'll be down  in maintenance, okay?  Al!
艾尔 什么事？
What?  Hey, Al.
艾尔 干嘛？
What?  Remember you sent  some wildcatters...
你记不记得你上个礼拜 派人到异形区调查的结果
out to the middle  of nowhere last week,  out past the Ilium Range?
记得，怎么了？
- Yeah, what?  - One of them's on the horn,  a mom-and-pop survey team.
有人回报说他们找到些东西
想知道结果有没有他一份
He says he's onto something.  He wants to know if  his claim will be honored.
为什么不呢？
Why wouldn't his claim  be honored?
因为是你派他到那个鬼地方去
Well, because you sent them to that  particular middle-of-nowhere  on company orders, maybe.
我们只是奉上级的命令行事 他们也没有解释原因
I don't know.  Christ! Some honch in  a cushy office on Earth...
says, "Go look at  a grid reference."
我也不会多问
We look.  They don't say why,  and I don't ask.
我不问是因为 要等两个星期才有答案
I don't ask, because it takes  two weeks to get an answer out here,  and the answer is always-
而答案总是“不要多问”
[ Together ]  "Don't ask."
我要怎么跟他说呢？
So what do l  tell this guy?  [ Sighs ]
告诉他，据我个人意见 他找到的东西就归他
Tell him as far as  I'm concerned, if he  finds something, it is his.
莱特克 干什么？
Lydecker?  What?
小孩不可以到这里来，快走
[ Giggling ]  You kids know you're not  supposed to be on this level!
Go on!  Get outta here!  [ Giggling ]
你专门跑到我们去不了的地方
[ Boy ] Do too. You go  in places we can't fit.  So? That's why I'm the best.
那又怎么样？谁叫我比你好
别闹了，别让我再抓到 你们两个到不该去玩的地方玩
Knock it off! I catch either  of you playing in the air ducts  again, l'll tan your hides.
妈，所有的小朋友都…
Mom, all the kids play-
等等，安妮，过来看看
Wait a minute.  Annie, come and have  a look at this, will ya?
我们这次挖到宝了
Folks, we have  scored big this time.
那是什么啊？
What is it, Dad?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
看看我们能不能靠近一点看
Let's see if we can't get a  closer look at this thing, maybe  through that crack there on the side.
我们该先向基地报告吧？
- Shouldn't we call in?  - Let's wait till we know  what to call it in as.
先看看这东西到底是什么
[ Brakes Hiss ]  [ Dad ] That's about as close  as we can get.
我们只能靠这么近了
要不要进去看看？
Should we take  a look inside?
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
你们两个留在里面 我们马上回来
You two stay inside.  I mean it.  We'll be right back.
再见
Okay.  Bye.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Radio Chatter, Indistinct ]
Huh?
他们去了好久
Timmy, they've been gone  a long time.
他们不会有事的
It'll be okay, Newt.  Dad knows what he's doing.
爸爸知道他在做什么
[ Banging ]  Mayday, Mayday! This is Alpha Kilo  Two Four Niner calling!
This is Alpha Kilo  Two Four Niner!
[ Screaming ]  Alpha Kilo  Two Four Niner calling!
[ Meowing ]
[ Doorbell Beeps ]
[ Clears Throat ]
嗨，蕾普莉
Hiya, Ripley.  This is Lieutenant Gorman...
这是殖民地的高曼中尉
of the Colonial  Marine Corps-
我们得谈谈
Ripley,  we have to talk.
我们与LV426失去联络
We've lost contact  with the colony on LV-426.
我真的不能相信
I don't believe this.
你们已曾丢我去那儿
You guys throw me at the wolves,  and now you want me  to go back out there?
现在又叫我回去？
免谈，这不是我的问题
Forget it.  It's not my problem.
我可以说完吗？
Can I finish?  No.  There's no way.
不，没可能
你不必进去，我保证你的安全
Ripley, you wouldn't  be going in  with the troops.
I can guarantee  your safety.
这些殖民陆战队都是顶尖的
These Colonial Marines  are very tough hombres.
拥有最尖端的火力装备
They're packing  state-of-the-art  firepower.
什么状况都能应付
There's nothing  they can't handle.
中尉，对吗？
- Lieutenant, am I right?  - That's true.
完全正确
We've been trained  to deal with situations  like this.
接受训练就为了应付这种状况
你们不需要我，我不是军人
Then you don't need me.  I'm not a soldier.
可是我们不知道情况如何
[ Burke ]  Yeah, but we don't know exactly  what's going on out there.
也许只是通讯器故障
It mayjust be  a downed transmitter,  okay?
如果不是的话…
But if it's not,  I would like you there  as an adviser,
我希望你做我们的顾问
就这么简单
and that's all.
What's your interest  in all this?  Why are you going?
这件事对你有什么好处？ 你为什么要去
Corporation cofinanced  that colony,
那个殖民地是我们出资支持的
along with  Colonial Administration.
我们现在要进行 广大的开垦计划
We're getting into a lot  of terraforming now.  "Building Better Worlds"-
建造一个更好的世界… 我看过广告了
Yeah, yeah.  I saw the commercial.
我没时间跟你搞 我还有事要做
Look, I don't have time  for this. I've got  to get to work.
是了，听说你在货柜码头工作
Oh, right. I heard you're  working the cargo docks.
对
That's right.
忙着装货补货吗？
Running loaders and forklifts,  that sort of thing?  Yeah. So?
是呀，怎样？
Nothing. I think it's great  that you're keeping busy.
没事，让自己忙一点很好
我知道你也只能干这种差事
And I know it's the only  thing that you could get.
这没有什么不对
There's nothing wrong  with it.
如果我能使你再当飞行官呢？
What would you say  if I told you I could  get you reinstated...
公司方面同意和你签约
as a flight officer?
The company's already agreed  to pick up your contract.  If I go.
只要我肯去
Yeah, if you go.
对，只要你肯去
Come on.  That's a second chance, kiddo.
来吧！第二春呢
而且我认为必须要去面对
I think, personally,  for you, it would be  the best thing in the world...
你才有机会克服
to get out there  and face this thing,  get back on the horse.
放过我，我刚看过心理医生
Spare me, Burke.  I've had my psych evaluation  this month.
我知道，你每晚醒来直冒冷汗
Yeah, I know. I've read it. You wake  up every night. Your sheets  are soaking with sweat-
我说不就是不
I said no,  and I mean it!
请你走吧，我不回去
Now, please leave.  I am not going back.
我回去对你也没有好处
And I am- I would not be  any good to you if I did.
好吧
Okay. Shh.
帮我个忙，考虑一下
Would you  do me a favor?  Just think about it.
谢谢你的咖啡
Thanks  for the coffee.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Meows ]
[ Screaming, Panting ]
Oh!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Water Running ]
[ Beeping ]
Hello.
蕾普莉
Ripley.
你还好吧？
You okay?  Just tell me  one thing, Burke.
告诉我一件事，巴克
你要去毁灭它们，对吗？
You're going out there  to destroy them, right?
不是研究，也不是带回来
Not to study, not to bring back,  but to wipe them out.
而是消灭它们
这就是了，我保证
That's the plan.  You have my word on it.
好吧，我去
All right. I'm in.
I think that-
至于你
And you,  you little shithead,
你留下来
[ Chuckles ]  you're staying here.
[ Creaking ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Whirring ]
Mmm.
[ Coughing ]
[ Groans ]
他们这次付的钱还不够多
They ain't payin' us  enough for this, man.
不够把你叫醒吗？
Not enough  to have to wake up  to your face, Drake.
什么？这是笑话吗？
What?
希望是
Is that a joke?
Oh, I wish it were.
希克斯老兄
Hey, Hicks. Man, you look  just like I feel.  [ Grunts ]
你的样子就像我这么逊
- [ Coughing ]  - All right, sweethearts.  What are you waiting for?
大伙，等什么？等人送饭吗？
又是全新的一天
Breakfast in bed?  Another glorious day  in the corps.
陆战队的日子吃得好，赚得多
A day in the Marine Corps  is like a day on the farm-
还能大干一场，我爱死陆战队
every meal's a banquet,  every paycheck a fortune,  every formation a parade.
地板冰死人了
I love the corps!  Christ!
Man, this floor is freezing!
你要我怎样？帮你拿拖鞋？
What do you want me to do?  Fetch your slippers for ya?  Gee, would you, sir? I'd like that.
可以吗？那最好
看着我
Look into my eye.  Fall in, people.
集合了，大伙，快点
Come on. Let's go.
我不喜欢这差事
I hate this job.
快点
Crowe, Wierzbowski.  Come on. On your feet.  We got some slack coming, right?
You had three weeks  on your back, Frost.  What do you want?
[ Frost ]  I'm talking about breathing,  not this frozen shit.
[ Dietrich ]  Yeah, Top. How 'bout it?
到十五区开会，过去集合
[Apone ]  All right. First assembly's  in 15, people. Shag it.
米拉，白雪公主是谁？
Hey, mira.  Who's Snow White?
应该就是见过异形的女顾问
She's supposed to be  some kind of consultant.
Apparently,  she saw an alien once.
真有一套
Whoopee-fuckin'-do!  Hey, I'm impressed.
我真佩服她
iQue bonita!
我不敢相信
娃丝佳，你被误认成男人吗？
Hey, Vasquez.  Have you ever been  mistaken for a man?
没有，你呢？
No. Have you?
Ha, ha!  Oh, Vasquez.  You're just too bad.
你真是太悍了
Uhh!
[ Chattering ]
老大，什么任务？
Hey, Top,  what's the op?
救援行动，你会喜欢的
It's a rescue mission.  You'll love it.
我们要解救殖民地 移民女儿的贞操
There's some juicy  colonists' daughters we have  to rescue from their virginity.
移民笨蛋
[ Spunkmeyer]  Dumb-ass colonists.
这是什么烂东西？
What's this crap  supposed to be?  Vasquez.
玉米饼吧
Corn bread, I think.  It's good for you, boy.  Eat it.
对你有好处，吃吧
我不介意再找一些肉蛋
Hey, sure wouldn't mind  getting some more  of that Arcturian poontang.
记得吗？
- Remember that time?  - Yeah. Except the one  that you had was male.
对呀，你那只是公的
当是肉蛋没有关系
Doesn't matter  when it's Arcturian.
主教，表演一下吧
Hey, Bishop, man.  Do the thing with the knife.  Oh, please.
快呀，来吧
Oh, come on. Yeah.  [ All Goading ]
All right! Yeah.
我不要看
- I don't want to see that, man.  - Come on, man.  All right. All right.
你在干嘛？别搞我，垂克
Hey, what are you doing, man?  What are you doing?
Come on.  Quit messing around, Drake.  Hudson, shut up !
主教，老兄
- Bishop, hey, man.  - [ Drake ] Do it, Bishop!
动手，主教
Hey! Not me, man!  Quit messing around!  Yeah, you! Don't move.
我不要
别动
Trust me.
相信我
Aah!
好了，别闹了
[Apone ]  All right. Knock it off,  knock it off.
谢谢你
- Thank you.  - [ Drake Chuckles ]
吃你的晚餐吧
There you go,  short shit.  Enjoy your meal.
这不好笑
That wasn't funny, man.
高曼中尉？巴克先生？
Lieutenant Gorman?  Mr. Burke?  Yeah, thanks.
好，谢谢
Looks like the new lieutenant's  too good to eat with  the rest of us grunts.
新任中尉不肯跟我们同桌吃饭
落水狗上岸，抖起来了
Boy's definitely got  a corncob up his ass.
我以为你从不会失手
[ Burke ]  Thought you  never miss, Bishop.
你怎么不早说船上有生化人
You never said anything about  an android being on board.  Why not?
我没想到，这很平常
[ Chuckles ]  It never-  never occurred to me.
船上一向都有生化人
It's just common practice.  We always have  a synthetic on board.
我比较喜欢被称为“人造人”
I prefer the term  "artificial person" myself.
Right.
有问题吗？
- Is there a problem?  - [ Burke ] I'm sorry.
抱歉，我不知道为什么…
I don't know why  I didn't even-
蕾普莉上次因生化…
Ripley's last trip out,  the syn- the artificial person  malfunctioned.
人造人故障…
- Malfunctioned?  - There were problems and  a few deaths were involved.
故障
发生问题，有些人被害死
真是想不到
I'm shocked.  Was it an older model?
旧的那一型吗？
The Hyperdyne Systems  1 20-A2.
120-A2型
这就难怪，A2型常常有问题
That explains it then.  The A2s always were  a bit twitchy.
现在我们这些新生代 不会有这种情形
That could never happen now  with our behavioral inhibitors.
我绝对不会伤害人类
It is impossible for me to harm,  or by omission ofaction, allow  to be harmed, a human being.
你真的不要？
- You sure you  don't want some?  - [ Clattering ]
离我远点，主教，明白吗？
You just stay away from me,  Bishop. You got that straight?
我猜她也不喜欢玉米饼
Guess she don't like  the corn bread, either.
[ Chattering ]
部队立正，长官驾临
[ Apone ] Squad, ten-hut!  Officer on deck!  As you were.
稍息
快点，快点，站好
Quickly, quickly.  Settle down.
好了，听好
All right.  Listen up!
早安，陆战队员
Morning, marines. l'm sorry we  didn't have time to brief you  people before we left Gateway-
很抱歉离开基地前没时间说明
长官
[ Hudson ]  Sir?  What is it, Hicks?
什么事？希克斯
Hudson, sir.  He's Hicks.
是哈德逊，长官
他才是希克斯
What's the question?
什么问题？
这是一场战斗还是除虫行动？
Is this gonna be  a stand-up fight, sir,  or another bug hunt?
目前只知道还没和移民联络上
All we know is that  there's still no contact  with the colony...
还有一种异形侵入
and that a xenomorph  may be involved.
抱歉，什么？
Excuse me, sir.  A what?  A xenomorph.
异形
It's a bug hunt.
这是除虫行动
敌人到底是谁？
- What exactly are  we dealing with here?  - Ripley.
蕾普莉
我会把经过说出来
I'll tell you  what I know.
我们降落在LV426
We set down  on LV-426.
队员把附在脸上的东西带回去
One ofour crew members was  brought back on board with  something attached to his face,
类似寄生虫的东西
some kind of parasite.
我们试着弄下来，可是没办法
We tried to get it off.  It wouldn't come off.
后来好像脱皮而死
Later, it seemed to come off  by itselfand die.
肯恩的气色不错
Kane seemed fine.
我们一起用晚餐
We were all having dinner,  and, um,
它一定在他体内产卵
it must have laid something  inside his throat,  some sort of embryo.
然后他就开始…
He started- Um, he-  [ Vasquez ]  Look, man.
听着，大姐
I only need  to know one thing-  where they are.
我只想知道它在那里？
干掉它
Yo, Vasquez.  Kick ass.  Anytime, anywhere.
随时随地
Right, right. Somebody said  "alien." She thought they said  "illegal alien" and signed up.
有人一提到异形
她就以为是非法移民
去你的
Fuck you, man.  Anytime,  anywhere.
随时奉陪
Are you finished?
够了没？
希望你说的对，真的
I hope you're right.  I really do.
好了，谢谢你，蕾普莉
Yeah, okay, right.  Thank you, Ripley.
磁碟片上也有她的报告
We also have Ripley's  report on disk.  I suggest you study it.
我建议你们研究一下
Because just one of those things  managed to wipe out my entire crew  in less than 24 hours.
那只异形在24小时内 消灭我全船人员
如果移民发现那艘船
And if the colonists  have found that ship,  then there's no telling...
不知道有多少只已经在活动
how many of them  have been exposed.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
全都在磁碟片上，最好去看看
Anyway, we have it on disk,  so you better look at it.
还有问题吗？
Any questions?
什么事？二等兵
What is it, Private?
我该怎么脱离这胆小部队？
How do I get out of this  chickenshit outfit?
给我闭嘴，哈德逊
You secure that shit,  Hudson.
好吧
All right.
现在听好
Now listen up.
我要大家按规矩，好好地干
I want this thing  to go smooth...
and by the numbers.
早上八点半携带战略资料
I want D.C.S.  and tactical database  assimilation by 0830.
全副武装，全体动员
[ All Scoffing ]  Ordinance loading, weapons strip  and drop-ship prep details...
离行动时间有七小时
will have  seven hours.  Oh, come on.
动手吧，各位
Now, move it,  people!
你们听到中尉的话，赶快行动
All right, sweethearts.  You heard the man,  and you know the drill.
哈德逊，过来，给我过来
Assholes and elbows!  Hudson, come here.  Come here.
我不管，哈德逊，快去做
I don't care if you  are short, Hudson.  Get it done.
士官长，抽雪茄会得口腔癌
Hey, Sarge.  You'll get lip cancer  smoking those.
我要这舱口关闭，快点
Corporal, I want this  loading lock sealed.  Now!
还有多少没弄好，史都麦？
How many more you got,  Spunkmeyer?  Last one.
最后一个
Good. Take it away.
把它弄好
[ Whirring, Thudding ]
小心后面
Clear behind.
检查过3区吗？
Did you check number three?  Let me see that.
我在游手好闲，可以帮忙吗？
Hi. I feel like kind of  a fifth wheel around here.  Is there anything I can do?
我不知道，你能做什么？
I don't know.  Is there anything  you can do?
我能操作起重机械人
Well, I can drive  that loader.
我有2等级数
I have a Class 2 rating.
请便
Be my guest.
[ Whirring ]
放哪儿？
- Where you want it?  - [ Chuckles ]
请放到12区
[ Laughing ]  Bay 12, please.
[ Engines Revving ]
你们是一队，没什么好担心的
[Apone ] All right,  sweethearts. We're a team, and  there's nothing to worry about.
我们前来，是要奋力杀敌
We come here,  and we gonna conquer,  and we gonna kick some.
明白吗？
Is that understood? That's what  we gonna do, sweethearts.  Yes, sir.
明白
咱们就这么干，大家好好表现
We are going to go  and get some.  Hey.
好了，到预备位置
All right, people!  On the ready line!
你们狠吗？
Are you lean?  Are you mean?  [All ] Yeah! Yeah!
是
够狠吗？
What are you?  What are you?  Lean and mean!
你们是什么？
陆战队
到预备位置
Hudson!  Get on the ready line,  marine!
动身了
快，快，快
Get some today!  Get on the ready line!
走，走，走
Yo!  Move it out!  Move it out, goddamn it!
Get hot! One, two, three!  Get out, get out, get out!
Move it out, move it out,  move it out! Move it out,  move it out, move it out!
[ Barking Orders,  Indistinct ]
[ Growls ]  Absolutely badasses.
真是一群悍将
上车了，进去
Let's pack 'em in.  Get in there!
快点
All right! Move it!
Let's go, let's go!  One, two, three,
four, five, six!
好了，战斗位置，大家都知道
All right.  I want combat seating.  You know your places.
武器放好，快
Get those weapons stowed.  Let's go.
大家坐好
Come on.  Settle down, people.
锁好，哈德逊
Lock 'em in, Hudson.
上路吧
Ready to get it on?  You know it!
主教，起飞吧
Okay, Bishop,  let's go.
收到
Roger.
我准备好了，哥儿们
I'm ready, man.
准备大干一场
Ready to get it on!  Go!  [ Murmurs Of Agreement ]
走
预备，锁门，闸门关闭
[ Ferro On Headsets ]  Stand by. Cross-locking now.  Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
主连结器脱离
Primary couplers released.  Hit the internals.
开启主动力
确认锁紧及发射安全
Shit, man.  Confirm cross-lock  and drop stations secured.
确定发射安全
[ Gorman ]  Affirmative.  All drop stations secured.
预备，十秒钟
Stand by. Ten seconds.
照我的口令，准备发射
Stand by to initiate  release sequencer...  on my mark.
我们正在下地狱，下去了
- Five, four, three,  - We're on an express elevator  to hell, going down.
…2…1…发射
two, one, mark.
Woo-hoo!
转到DCS地形图
- Switch to D.C.S. ranging.  - [ Spunkmeyer]  240, nominal to profile.
表面纵剖面图240度
我们上5X5航道
We're in the pipe,  five by five.
正通过电离层
We're picking up  some hull ionization.
前面有乱流，正冲过去
Got it.  Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.  [ Rumbling ]
中尉，你有几次飞行经验？
How many drops is this  for you, Lieutenant?
38次
Thirty-eight.
模拟飞行
Simulated.
几次战斗经验？
How many combat drops?
两次，包括这次
Uh, two...  including this one.
惨了
- Shit.  - Oh, man!
014度，准备降落
Range 014.  Turning on final.
我告诉你，我有个坏预兆
[ Frost ] And I'm telling you,  I got a bad feeling  about this drop.
你老是这么说
[ Crowe ] You always say that,  Frost. You always say, "I got  a bad feeling about this drop."
好吧，万一你回不去
[ Frost ]  Okay, okay.  When we get back without you,
我会通知你父母
I'll call your folks.  [ Laughs ]  [ Beeping ]
好了，让我看看
All right.  Let's see what we can see.
大家都在，精神很好
Everybody online.  Looking good.
垂克，你的电眼好像故障
Drake, check your camera.  There seems to be  a malfunction.
好多了
That's better.  Pan it around a bit.
移动一下，好
- Good.  - I'm ready, man. Check it out.
你们看，我是最强战士
I am the ultimate badass.  Yeah.  That's right.
最好别惹我
State-of-the-badass art.  You do not want to fuck with me.  Who here's runnin'?
你看
Check it out.  [ Chuckles ]
蕾普莉，别担心 我和我的兄弟会保护你的
Hey, Ripley,  don't worry.
Me and my squad of  ultimate badasses  will protect you.
Hey!  That's right.
看…
Check it out.
这是独立瞄准粒子枪系统
Independently targeting  particle-beam phalanx.
包准把异形烧成焦炭
[ Imitates Blast Noise ]  Fry halfa city  with this puppy.
还有导弹系统 还有最先进的太空武器
We got tactical  smart missiles,
phase-plasma pulse rifles,  R.P.G.'s.
还有超音波电子枪
- We got sonic,  electronic ball breakers!  - [ Vasquez ] Whoo!
我们有核子武器，还有…
We got nukes, we got knives,  sharp sticks-
别闹了，韩森
Knock it off, Hudson.  All right, gear up.
大家准备好
各位准备行动
Two minutes, people.  Get hot.
把西克斯叫醒吧
Somebody wake up Hicks.
接近709度
Coming around  for a 709er.
自动导航锁定
Terminal guidance  locked in.  Where's the damn beacon?
该死的信号在哪里？
Oh, I see it.
看到了
那就是大气处理机？
That's the atmosphere  processor?  Yep, that's it.
没错，就是它
顶尖的科技，全自动化
Remarkable piece  of machinery.  Completely automated.
我们也生产这玩意
You know,  we manufacture those,  by the way.
好，弗洛
[ Gorman ] Okay, Ferro.  Take us in low over  the main colony complex.
带我们到殖民地的主要区域
雨窗关闭，没有可见活动
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity.  All right. Hold at 40.
好，稳住40英里前进
知道
[ Ferro On Headset ] Roger.  Give me a slow circle  of the complex.
慢慢绕着建筑物飞
结构似乎完整
Structure seems intact.  They still have power.
他们仍有电力
Okay, Ferro.  Set down on  the landing grid.
好了，弗洛，降落吧
清除视觉障碍，随时待命
Immediate dust off  on my clear,  then stay on station.
可以发动
[ Ferro ]  Down and clear.
十秒钟，提起精神
Ten seconds, people.  Look sharp.
咱们来个漂亮分散队形
All right. I want a nice,  clean dispersal this time.
走吧，快点，来吧
Let's go!  Move it out!
Head 'em up!
第一队就位
First squad up on line.  Hicks, get yours in accord  and watch the rear.
希克斯，你殿后
娃丝佳带头，前进
Vasquez, take point.  Let's move!
前进
Move up.
哈德逊，把电门弄开
Hudson, run a bypass.
第二队前进，掩护队形
Second squad, move up.  Flanking positions.
第二队就位
[ Apone Over Headsets ]  Second squad on line.
[ Door Lock Clicks ]
好了没？
[ Whispers ]  You set?
Go on.
第二队往里面走
Second team, move inside.  Hicks, take the upper level.
希克斯，搜上面的通道
长官，你看到吗？
[ Apone ]  Sir, you copying this? Looks  like hits from small-arms fire.
看来是被轻型武器攻击
像是地震引起的爆炸损害
Uh, we got some  explosives damage.
It's probably seismic  survey charges.
你听到吗？
Are you reading this?  Keep it tight, people.
跟紧点
希克斯，哈德逊
[ Gorman ]  All right. Hicks, Hudson,  use your motion trackers.
用你们的行动追踪器
[ Clicking ]
什么迹象都没有
Nothing.  Not a goddamn thing.
两人一组搜索
Quarter and search  by twos.
[ Snaps Fingers ]
迪杰，法斯，你们上
Okay. Dietrich,  Frost, you're up.
[ Sniffs ]
[ Clicking Continues ]
[ Beeping ]
It's right in there.
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
Now!  Now!
- Haah! Uh-  - Good one, Hudson!
[ Hudson ] Uh, sir, uh, we have  a negative situation here.  Uh, movin' on, sir
[ Clicking ]
等等，叫他们…
Wait. Wait,  tell him to-
希克斯，后退
Hicks, back up.  Pan right.
镜头移向右边
- There.  - You seeing this all right?
看这里
看得到吗？像是被腐蚀过
Looks melted.  Somebody must have bagged  one of Ripley's bad guys here.
看来是杀死蕾普莉队员的东西
硫酸血？
Acid for blood.
你喜欢那个，更会爱死这个
If you like that,  you're gonna love this.
[ Hocking ]
别闹了
Quit screwing around.
第二队，情况如何？
Second squad,  what's your status?
我们刚检查完，没有人
[ Hicks ]  Uh, we just finished our sweep.  Nobody's home.
知道了
Roger.  Sir, this place is dead.
长官，这是死城
不管发生什么事，我们都错过
Whatever happened here,  I think we missed it.
这地方安全，去看看电脑
[ Sighs ] All right. The area's  secured. Let's go in and see  what their computer can tell us.
有什么好看的？
等一下
- Wait a minute.  It's not secure.  - The area's secured, Ripley.
还不安全
安全了，蕾普莉
First team,  head for operations.
第一队，向主控室前进
哈德逊，接上他们的CUP
Hudson, see if you can  get their C.P.U. on line.  Affirmative.
遵命
Hicks, meet me at  the south lock. We're coming in.  Roger.
希克斯，在南门等我，我来了
收到
He's comin' in.  I feel safer already.
他要进来，我觉得好安全
Pendejo jerk-off.
我们已经和GCU连线了 没有问题
[ Hudson On Radio ]  Sir, we got the C.P.U. on line.  No problem.
准备行动
Good. Stand by  in Operations.
我们走吧
Okay, let's go.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我没事
Yes.
长官，他们封锁区域的两端
Sir, they sealed off  this wing at both ends,
舱门封住，楼梯被重物塞着
welded the doors  and blocked off the stairs  with heavy equipment.
看起来阻碍物好像没作用
[ Gorman ] Mm-hmm.  But it looks like  the barricade didn't hold.
有尸体吗？
Any bodies?  No, sir.
没有，长官
最后一站
Last stand.
看来打过一场大战
[ Drake ]  Must have been  a hell ofa fight.
是啊，好像是
Yeah, looks that way.
好了，垂克，这边
也许能从化验室到主控室
[ Gorman ]  All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able  to cut through the medlab  to Operations.
中尉
[ Hicks ]  Lieutenant.
高曼
Gorman.
跟你说的一样吗？
Are those the same ones that-
小心点，巴克
Careful, Burke.
看来它对你一见钟情
Looks like love  at first sight to me.
它喜欢你，巴克
Oh, he likes you, Burke.  [ Chuckles ]
两个还活着，其余死了
Two are alive.  The rest are dead.
进行割除异体胚胎时
"Surgically removed  before embryo implantation.
约翰死于手术中
Subject Marachek, John J.,  died during the procedure."
他们杀了他
They killed him  taking it off.
[ Clicking, Beeping ]  Yo, Hicks.
希克斯
我看有动静了
I think we got  something here.
在我们后面
Behind us.  One of us?
我们的人吗？
阿朋，你的人都在吗？
Apone, where are your people?  Anybody in "D" block?
有人在D区吗？
没有，我们都在主控室
[ Apone On Radio ]  Ah, that's a negative.  We're all in Operations.
快回答，法斯
Talk to me,  Frosty.
继续走
Let's keep moving, baby.
[ Crash ]
在动了
It's moving.  Which way?
哪里？
It's coming  straight for us.  Straight up.
朝着我们来，一直来
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
可恶
Fuck!  Hold up.
慢点
蕾普莉
Ripley.
没事了，没事了
Hey. Shh.  It's all right.
捉住她，下士
It's all right.  Come on.  Just grab her, Corporal.
别怕，过来
Don't be afraid. Come on.  We won't hurt you.
我们不会害你，没有关系
Shh. It's all right.  It's okay.
出来，出来，慢慢来
Come on out. Come on.
我捉到了
- Easy. Easy.  - I got her.
可恶
Ow! Damn!
别让她跑了
Watch her!  She's under the grille!  Don't let her go.
把灯照过来
Frost, get your light  up here.  Where'd she go?
她跑到哪里？
开灯
Shine the light.  Here. Here.
这里，这里
Here. Here.  There she is.
退后，退后，别吓到她
[ Ripley ]  Keep back. Keep back.  Don't scare her.
捉住她，她会跑掉
[ Hicks ] Grab her, man.  We're gonna lose her.  [ Ripley ] Damn it!
可恶
[ Hicks ]  Kick it out!
等等
[ Grunts ]  Wait.
[ Clattering ]
好了，没事了
It's okay.  It's all right.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
看
See?
等等，不，不可以
Wait.  No, you don't.  [ Screams ]
没事的
It's okay.  You're gonna  be all right now.
你会没事的
[ Whimpering ]  Shh.
慢点，慢点，你会没事的
Easy. Easy.  It's gonna be okay.
静下来，静下来
It's all right.  You're gonna be okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
[ Whirring ]
她叫什么名字？
What's her name again?  Rebecca.
韦碧琪
回想一下，韦碧琪，专心想
Now think, Rebecca.  Concentrate.
从头开始想，你父母在哪里？
Just start  at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
你必须…
Now, look, Rebecca,  you have to try and help-
高曼，让她休息吧
Gorman, give it a rest,  why don't you?
头壳坏掉了
[ Sighs ]  Total brain lock.
她的身体很好
Physically, she's okay.
只是营养不良，不会有大碍
Borderline malnutrition,  but I don't think there's  any permanent damage.
走吧，我们在浪费时间
Come on.  We're wasting our time.
喝这个
Try this.
热巧克力
It's a little  hot chocolate.
喝吧
There you go.
Whoop.
不错吧
That good, huh?
我帮你擦一下，好了
Uh-oh. I made  a clean spot here.
看来我得擦干净
Now I've done it.  Guess l'll have to  do the whole thing.
很难想像这里还有个小女孩
Hard to believe  there's a little girl  under all this.
而且很漂亮
And a pretty one too.
你不喜欢讲话，对吧？
You don't talk much,  do you?
吸烟区，还是非吸烟区
Smoking  or nonsmoking?
告诉我你在扫瞄什么？
Just tell me what  you're scanning for, Private.
PDTS，私人资料转换器
P.D.T.s.  What?
每个移民都有植入
Personal data  transmitters.
Every colonist had one  surgically implanted.
二十公里内可以测到
If they're  within 20 klicks,  we'll read it out here.
但目前为止，什么都没有
So far, zippo.
我不知道你怎么活下来
I don't know how you  managed to stay alive,
不过你很勇敢，韦碧琪
but you're one  brave kid, Rebecca.
妞特
[ Whispers ]  N-Newt.
你说什么？
- What'd you say?  - Newt.
妞特，我叫妞特
My name's Newt.
除了我哥哥，没人叫我韦碧琪
Nobody calls me Rebecca  except my brother.
妞特，好名字
Newt?  I like that.
我是蕾普莉，很高兴认识你
I'm Ripley.  It's nice to meet you.
这是谁？
And who is this, hmm?
卡西
Casey.  Hello, Casey.
哈罗，卡西
你哥哥呢？他叫什么？
What about your brother?  What's his name?
添美
Timmy.
添美也在吗？
Is Timmy around here too?  Maybe hiding like you were?
也许跟你一样藏起来
你还有姐妹吗？
Any sisters?
爸妈呢？
Mom and dad?
妞特，看着我
Newt, look at me.  Where are they?
他们在那里？
They're dead, all right?  Can I go now?
他们死了，我可以走吗？
很遗憾，妞特
I'm sorry, Newt.
你和我们在一起比较安全
Don't you think you'd  be safer here with us?
那些人会保护你，他们是军人
These people are here  to protect you.
那也没有用
They're soldiers.
It won't make  any difference.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Cart's Wheels Clacking ]
还要什么吗？
Need anything else?
主教，你还要什么？
Hello, Bishop. Do you  need anything else?
不要
No.
你的宠物很可爱，主教
That's a nice pet  you got there, Bishop.
很棒，是不是？
Magnificent, isn't it?
别管别的事，我找到了
Yo! Stop your grinnin'  and drop your linen! Found 'em.
还活着吗？
They alive?  Unknown,
不知道，看来到处都是
but it looks  like all of them.
它们在加工厂，地下三楼
Over at the processing station,  Sublevel 3,
主冷冻库也有
under the main  cooling towers.
看来它们在那里集合
Looks like  a goddamn town meeting.
整装出发，阿朋
Let's saddle up, Apone.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
All right. Let's go, people.  They ain't payin' us  by the hour.
出发了
Let's go.  Head 'em out!
好，法斯，你开车
Okay, Frost,  you're driving.
没事的，别担心，一切都没事
It's okay. Don't worry.  It'll be okay.
镇暴队形
[ Gorman On Radio ] I want  a straight "V" deployment,  second team on left flank.
第二队左翼，方位664前进
Advance on axial 664.  Tracker on line.
镜头打开，队形前进包围RF
Set the "V" gain  to filter R.F. ambient.
哈德逊，打开镜头
[ Apone ]  Hudson, tracker on line.  Left and right, little buddy.
左，右，各位
四十米，方位221 应该有楼梯
[ Clicking ]
[ Gorman ]  Forty meters in, bearing 221 ,  there should be a stairwell.
有
Check. Got it.
目的地，地下三楼
[ Gorman ]  You want Sublevel 3.
快点，各位
[ Apone ]  Let's go, people.  Hudson, you got the point.
哈德逊，你开路
Hicks, watch our tails.
希克斯，你殿后
慢慢来，检查角落
Nice and easy.  Check those corners.
检查角落
Check those corners.
保持距离
Watch your spacing.  [ Apone ] All right.  You heard the man.
听到没有，别乱走
摄影机有点视讯不良
Don't bunch up.  Stay loose.
[ Gorman ]  Uh, your transmission's  showing a lot ofbreakup.
可能受到建筑物干扰
[ Hudson ] Probably  getting some interference  from the structure.
用灯照
[ Apone ]  Use those lights.
另一个来了，向216区前进
[ Gorman ]  Next one down,  and proceed on a 216.
知道了，216区
[Apone ]  Uh, roger. That's a 216.
看不到是什么东西
[ Gorman ]  I'm not making that out  too well. What is it, Hudson?
你说呢？我也不知道
You tell me, man.  I only work here.
那是什么？
What is that?
不知道
I don't know.
前进
Proceed inside.
看到敌人再打
[ Apone On Headset ]  Watch your fire  and check your targets.
别忘了我们在找移民
Remember we're looking  for civvies in here.
别紧张
[ Apone ]  Easy.
跟紧点，法斯，你快脱队了
[ Hicks ]  Tighten it up, Frost.  We're getting a little thin.
慢慢来
[Apone ]  Nice and easy.
看起来像是树脂分泌物
Looks like some sort  of secreted resin.
没错，从哪儿来的？
Yeah, but secreted  from what?
什么都别碰
Nobody touch nothing.
这怪物还真有一套
Busy little  creatures, huh?
这里真的很热
Hot as hell in here.
对，不过这是闷热
Yeah, man,  but it's a dry heat.
别闹了，哈德逊
[Apone ]  Knock it off, Hudson.
中尉，这些电波枪火力如何？
Lieutenant, what do  those pulse rifles fire?
10公分口径高爆弹轻武器
Ten millimeter  explosive-tip caseless.
怎么了？
Standard light  armor-piercing round.
你的队员在主电源室下面
Why?  Well, look where  your team is.
They're right under  the primary  heat exchangers.
又怎样？
他们发射火力会波及冷却系统
So?
So if they fire their weapons  in there, won't they rupture  the cooling system?
她说的一点都没错
- Ho, ho, ho. Yeah.  She's absolutely right.  - So? So what?
又怎样？
基地原则上是座核子反应炉
Look. This whole station is  basically a big fusion reactor.
对吗？
Right?
她说的是热核子爆炸 一开火就完了
So you're talking about  a thermonuclear explosion,  and adios, muchachos.
很好，太棒了
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
听着
Look.  Uh... Apone.
阿朋
你们不能在里头开枪
[ Snapping Fingers ]
Look. We can't have  any firing in there.
我命令你把所有弹匣收起来
I, uh, I want you to collect  magazines from everybody.
你疯啦？
- Is he fuckin' crazy?  - What the hell are we supposed  to use, man, harsh language?
我们要用什么，用粗话骂？
只准用喷火枪，不准用机枪
- Flame units only.  I want rifles slung.  - Sir, I-
长官，我…
Just do it, Sergeant.  And no grenades.
快点，手榴弹也不行
好了，你们听到了，拿出来
All right, sweethearts.  You heard the man. Pull 'em out.  Come on. Let's have 'em.
来，娃丝佳，快点
Come on, Vasquez.  Clear and lock.
可恶
Damn!
你也一样，威伯斯基，拿来
You too. Give it up, Ski.  Come on. Let's go.
克罗
Crowe, I want it now.  Give it up.
我现在就要
拿来
干得好，娃丝佳
Right on, Vas.
陆战队员，全都拿来
Let's go, marine.  Give it up.
法斯，你负责，打开袋子
Frost, you got the duty.  Open that bag.
多谢了，士官长
- Thanks a lot, Sarge.  - Hicks, cover our ass.
希克斯，掩护我后面
向前走
Head 'em out, people.
我要这个作埋身肉博
I like to keep this handy...  for close encounters.
我听到了
I heard that.
[ Tracker Clicking ]
有动静吗？
[ Gorman ]  Any movement?
什么都没有
Nothing. Zip.
老天爷
Holy shit.
妞特，坐到前面
[ Ripley ]  Newt, go sit up front.
去啊，快点
Go on! Now!
慢慢来，我们要完成行动
[ Apone ]  Steady, people.  Let's finish our sweep.
我们陆战队要开工了
We're still marines,  and we got a job to do.
继续行动
Keep it moving. Easy.
小心点
救命啊
- Help!  - What?
什么事？
Top, get over here.  We got a live one!  You're gonna be all right.
那边有个活的
你不会有事的
拜托，杀了我吧
Please... k-kill me.
冷静点，我会救你的
[ Dietrich ]  Just stay calm.  We're gonna get you outta here.
你不会有事，帮我一下
It's gonna be all right.  Give me a hand.  We gotta get her outta here.
我们得救她出来
- What is it, Dietrich?  - Convulsion!
怎么回事？
她抽筋了
- [ Screaming ]  - Dietrich, get back!
退后
不
- Get back!  - [ Screams ]
- No!  - Frost, flamethrower.  Kill it!
杀了它
退后
Get back!  Flamethrower! Move!
发射喷火枪，快
[ Alien Screeches ]
- [ Groaning ]  - [ Screeching ]
[ Hissing ]
有动静了
[ Tracker Beeping ]  Movement!
哪个方向？
- What's the position?  - I can't lock in!
我无法锁定
怎么样？哈德逊
Talk to me, Hudson!
讯号繁复
Multiple signals.
它们接近中
They're closing.
用红外线镜，小心点
Go to infrared, people.  Look sharp!
怎么回事？什么也看不见
What's happening, Apone?  Can't see anything in here.
把部队撤回来，高曼
Pull your team out,  Gorman.
有讯号了，前面，后面
I got signals.  I got readings  in front and behind.
哪里？我怎么看不到
Where, man?  I don't see shit.
他说的对，这里没有东西
He's right.  There's nothing back here.
是真的，有东西，不是我们
Look, I'm telling you.  There's something moving,  and it ain't us!
他妈的
- Oh, shit.  - [ Hudson ]  Tracker's off scale, man.
到处都是，天哪
They're all  around us, man! Jesus!
可能用红外线看不到
Maybe they don't show up  on infrared at all.
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
法斯
- Frost!  - [ Screams ]
走吧
Come on!
老天，阿朋，发生什么事？
- [ Steady Beep ]  - Jesus Christ, Apone!  What is going on?
威伯斯基和克罗受伤
[ Hicks ]  Wierzbowski  and Crowe are down!
迪杰，克罗，关掉声音
Dietrich, Crowe!  Sound off! Frost!  Dietrich, Frost, off the board!
法斯，法斯
Frost!
威伯斯基，威伯斯基
[ Man Screaming ]  Wierzbowski?
- Wierzbowski?  - [ Wierzbowski Screaming ]
来吧！
[ Grunts ]  Let's rock!  [ Drake Shouting ]
[ Gunfire ]
谁在开火？该死
Who's firing?  Goddamn it!
我命令停火
Yeah!
I ordered to hold fire.  [ Hudson ] They're coming  out of the walls!
它们从墙上钻出来
They're coming out  of the goddamn walls!  Let's book!
阿朋，我要你们停火
[ Vasquez ]  On the right, man.  Uh, Apone,
I want you to lay down  a suppressing fire with the incinerators-
娃丝佳，垂克，停火
Vasquez, Drake,  hold your fire,  goddamn it!
阿朋，听到没有？停火
[ Gorman ] Apone, are you  copying me? I want you  to lay down suppressing fire...
离开焚化炉
with the incinerators  and fall back by squads  to the A.P.C.
重覆，全部退到焚化炉后
Over.  Say again,  all after "incinerator."
我要你们停火，退到…
I said I want you to lay down  a suppressing fire with  the incinerators and fall back...
by squads to the A.P.C.  Over.  [ Gunfire ]
救命
Hey!
[ Screaming ]
快说话，阿朋
- [ Hudson ] Sarge! Sarge!  - Apone.
Talk to me. Apone?  Copy! Copy!
他死了
Talk to me, Apone.  He's gone!
叫他们回来
住嘴
Get them out of there!  Shut up!
快点
Do it now! Hicks,  whoever's left, get-  Shut up!
闭嘴
希克斯，不管是谁
Just shut up!  Goddamn it!
可恶
阿朋在哪儿？
It's coming out of  the goddamn walls!  Where's Apone? Where's Apone?
士官长死了，我们赶快走
The sarge is gone!  Let's get the fuck out of here!
快走，快走
Let's move it!  Let's go, marine!
哈德逊
Hudson? Vasquez?
娃丝佳
哈德逊，小心
Hudson, look out!  Get it!
希克斯
[ Alien Screeching ]  Watch it!
Hicks.  Come on. Behind you!  Fall back!
我叫他们撤退
I told them to fall back.  [ Hicks ]  Fall back, goddamn it, now!
他们被切断，想想办法
They're cut off!  [ Hicks ]  Hudson, move your ass!
可恶
Do something!  [ Hicks ] Let's go, marine!
坐好，妞特
Fuck!
Come on.  Keep moving, baby.  Hold on, Newt.
[ Engines Revving ]
蕾普莉，你在干什么？
Ripley, what the hell  are you doing?
[ Tires Squealing ]
给我回去
Turn around!
这是命令
That's an order!
Get offme, damn it!  Goddamn it, that's an order!
你没机会了
You had your chance,  Gorman.
[ Tires Squealing ]
快点
Come on!
快点，走
- Come on. Let's move it!  - [ Screeches ]
快走
[ Vasquez ] Come on!  Let's go! Let's go!
快点，我们得快点
[ Hudson ] It's blocked, man.  We gotta go around!
去开门
- Open the door! Hicks!  - Drake, we are leaving!
希克斯
垂克，我们要走了
这些王八蛋
[ Drake ]  Get them, man!
Run for it!
该死
Shit!  [ Grunting ]
快走吧
[ Grunts ]  Go! Go!  [ Vasquez ] Come on, man! Come on!
垂克，快来呀
- Drake, come on!  - [ Screeches ]
不
- [ Screams ]  - No!
车上起火
- Fire in the hole!  - [ Hicks ] He's gone!
他没救了
Put it out! Put it out!  Go! Go!
快去灭火
- Come on. Put it out!  - Drake's coming, man!
他没救了
不，他没有…
Drake!  No, he's not!  He's gone!
算了，他死了
Forget him!  He's gone!
快关门
They're in the goddamn door!
吃子弹吧
Eat this!
- [ Screaming ]  - [ Hicks ] Ripley!
蕾普莉，走，走，走
Go, go, go!
[ Clatter]
没事了，我们脱身了
It's all right!  We're clear!  [ Metal Clattering ]
你弄坏了轴
Ripley, you've blown  the transaxle!
You're just  grinding metal!
放慢…放慢…放慢…
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down. Ease down.  Ease down.
[ Newt Coughing ]
你还好吗？
You okay?
我很好
l'm all right.  Hudson.
你的手怎样？ 不要你管
Get away from me, man!
中尉
Lieutenant.  What happened  to Gorman?
高曼如何？
不知道，也许撞到了，还活着
I don't know.  Maybe a concussion.
他死定了！醒醒，我要宰了你
But he's alive.  He's dead!
退后，快点
Wake up, pendejo, and then  I'm gonna kill you!
Back off.  Right now.
给我急救箱
Fuck!  Somebody get me  a first aid kit.
看，士官长和迪杰没死
Hey. Hey, look.
The sarge and Dietrich  aren't dead, man.
讯号很弱，不过还没死
Their signs are real low,  but they ain't dead.
我们回去救人
- Then we go back  in there and get them.  - Fuck that!
去你的
We don't leave our people behind―  I ain't going back in there.
我们不会留下战友
我才不回去
你们也没办法
You can't help them!
没有救了
You can't. Right now  they're being cocooned  just like the others.
他们会像其他人一样变成卵状
老天，不会吧
Oh, dear Lord Jesus,  this ain't happenin', man.  Damn it.
不可能
This can't be happenin', man.  This isn't happenin'!
我们有七支CN20散弹炮
All right. We got  seven canisters of CN-20.
我们用摧泪弹打它们
I say we roll them in there  and nerve gas  the whole fucking nest.
不过根本不知道有没有效
That's worth a try,  but we don't even know  if it's gonna affect them.
我们走吧，算平手好了
Let's just bug out and call it  even. Okay? What are we  talking about this for?
还说这些干嘛？
I say we take off  and nuke the entire  site from orbit.
最好从空中用核弹炸掉这地方
这是唯一的方法
It's the only way  to be sure.
真有一套
Fuckin' "A"!  Hold on.  Hold on one second.
慢点，慢点
这是很有价值的巨资工程
This installation has  a substantial dollar value  attached to it.
叫公司寄帐单给我
They can bill me.
慢点，大家都很激动
Okay, look.  This is an emotional moment  for all of us, okay?
我们不要开玩笑，拜托
I know that.  But let's not make  snap judgments, please.
我们面对的是很重要的生物
This is clearly-  clearly an important species  we're dealing with,
我不认为你们有权任意杀光它
and I don't think that  you or I or anybody  has the right...
- to arbitrarily  exterminate them.  - Wrong.
错了
Yeah. Watch us.
你等着瞧吧
Maybe you haven't been  keeping up on current events,
也许你瞎了，我们差点没命
but we just got  our asses kicked, pal!
我不是瞎子，我不同意这行动
Look. I'm not blind  to what's going on,
but I cannot authorize  that kind of action.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我相信希克斯下士有指挥权
Well, I believe  Corporal Hicks...
has authority here.
希克斯下士
Corporal Hicks is-
这是项军事行动
This operation  is under military  jurisdiction,
希克斯有第二指挥权
and Hicks is next  in chain of command.
对吗？下士
Am I right, Corporal?
对
Yeah.
对，没错
Yeah, that's right.
蕾普莉，这是很昂贵的工程
Yeah. Look, Ripley.  Yes.
This is a multimillion-dollar  installation, okay?
他不能乱下命令，他只是小兵
He can't make  that kind of decision.
He's just a grunt.  Uh, no offense.
别介意
None taken.  Ferro, do you copy?  Standing by.
没关系
弗洛，你听到吗？
准备好了
Prep for dust off.  We're gonna need  immediate evac.
我们马上撤退
收到，立即出发
Roger. On our way.
我说起飞后用核弹炸掉这地方
I say we take off,  nuke the site from orbit.  It's the only way to be sure.
这是唯一的方法
出发了
Let's do it.
是
[ Wind Whistling ]
抬起来，哈德逊，抬起来
Let's go.  Pick it up, Hudson.  Pick it up, baby.
好了，把他放下来
All right.  Set him down here.
快点，史巴梅尔，起飞了
Move it, Spunkmeyer.  We're rolling.
慢点，有东西…
Hold on a second.  There's something-
少罗唆，快上来
[ Ferro ]  Just get up here.
我进来了
I'm in. Ramp closing.
史巴梅尔
Spunkmeyer.
该死
Goddamn it.  [ Door Opens ]
你去哪儿了？
Well, where the fuck-
[ Hisses ]
快跑
Run!
完了，这下全完了
Well, that's great.  That's just fuckin' great, man.
现在该怎么办？
Now what the fuck  are we supposed to do?
我们现在可惨了
We're in some  real pretty shit now, man!
你好了没有？
Are you finished?
你还好吗？
You all right?
现在没办法走了，对不对？
I guess we're not gonna  be leaving now, right?
抱歉，妞特
I'm sorry, Newt.
你不必道歉，这不是你的错
You don't have to be sorry.  It wasn't your fault.  That's it, man.
完了，什么都完了
Game over, man!  Game over!
我们该怎么办？怎么办？
What the fuck  are we gonna do now?  What are we gonna do?
我们可以生个火，唱唱歌
Maybe we could build a fire.  Sing a couple of songs, huh?  Why don't we try that?
这样好不好？
天黑前得回去
We'd better get back  'cause it'll be dark soon,
它们都在夜间活动，多半都是
and they mostly  come at night, mostly.
全都在这儿吗？
That's everything, right?  All right. This is  absolutely everything...
对
这些都是失事船上能用的武器
that we could salvage  out of the A.P.C. wreckage.
四把50连发电波散弹枪
We got four pulse rifles  with about 50 rounds each.
并不太理想
That ain't so good.
还有15个M40手榴弹
We got, uh,  1 5 of these M-40 grenades.
别碰，危险，甜心
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey.  Is that the only  flamethrower?
那是唯一的喷火枪吗？
[ Hicks ]  Yeah. It's only half full,  but it's functional.
对，燃料只剩一半，还能用
另一个坏了，我不大清楚这支
Got another one, it's damaged―  I don't know about that one.
好消息是 我们有四套这种机械感应器
But the good news-  we got four of these  robot sentries,
而且大致都相当完好
with display  and scanners intact.
如果我们要消灭异形的话 这些应该派得上用场
They really kick ass.  I think they'll come in handy.
没按时回航，几时才有救援？
How long after  we're declared overdue  can we expect a rescue?
17天？
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
老兄，我不想扫兴
Hey, man, I don't wanna rain  on your parade, but we're  not gonna last 17 hours.
我们连17小时都撑不了
那怪物不会放过我们
Those things are gonna come in  here like they did before.  They're gonna come in here-
他们会…
Hudson! Hudson!  They're gonna come in here  and they're gonna get us!
哈德逊，哈德逊
这小女孩没有武器都活到现在
This little girl  survived longer than that...
with no weapons  and no training.
对吧？
Right?
让她指挥呀
Why don't you  put her in charge?
你最好要振作点
You'd better just start  dealing with it, Hudson.  Listen to me.
听我说，我们需要你，别罗唆
Hudson, just deal with it  because we need you.
And I'm sick  of your bullshit.
用电脑找出平面图，懂吗？
Now, I want you to get on  a terminal and call up  some kind of floor plan file.
建筑蓝图，这地方的平面图
Do you understand?  Construction blueprints.  I don't care.
Anything that shows  the layout of this place.  Are you listening?
你在听吗？
Yeah.  I need to see air ducts.
有
我要通风口，小通道，地下室
I need to see  electrical access tunnels,  subbasements,
任何能逃出这里的资料
every possible way  into this complex.
时间不多
- We don't have much time.  - Okay.
好，我去找
哈德逊，放轻松
Okay, I'm on it.  Hudson!
- Just relax.  - [ Exhales Sharply ]
我到化验室看高曼，继续研究
I'll be in medlab.  I'll check on Gorman,  continue my analysis.
很好，这样最好
Fine.  You do that.
它一定是走这条通道
So this service tunnel  must be how they're moving  back and forth.
没错
That's right.  It moves from  the processing station...
它们从处理室走到地下室
right into  the sublevel here.
下来一点，好，再过来
Come down on that.  Okay, come over.
回去，好，定点就是这里
Hold. Go back.  Okay, punch that in  right there.
不，回去
No. It's back here.  Okay.
这里有个压力舱
Well, there's  a pressure door  at this end.
把它关闭可以阻挡一阵子
Couldn't we put one of  the remote sentry units  in the tunnel and then seal that door?
它们可能从别处进来
Yeah, that'll work,  but we gotta figure on them  getting into the complex.
That's right,  so we repair the barricades  at these two intersections.
没错
在这些交叉点放置阻碍物
对
Right.  And weld plate steel  over these ducts...
再把通道封死，这里和这里
here and here and here.
阻止它到化验室及主控室
That way they can  only come at us  from these two corridors.
All right. Then we put  the other sentry units  here and here, right?
了不起，现在可以放心玩牌了
Right.  Outstanding.
Now all we need  is a deck of cards.
好了，照计划进行
All right, people.  Let's move like  we got a purpose.
遵命
[ Hudson ]  Affirmative.  Affirmative.
[ Beeping ]
我们封闭这通道
Do your thing, baby.  Come on, Vasquez.  Let's get the hell outta here.
宝贝，快点，快
我是哈德森 A和B感应器已经全部装好了
Hudson here.  "A" and "B" sentries  are in place and keyed.
待命，我们已经在准备武装了
Roger. Stand by.  Arming now.  Test it, Hudson.
可以了，哈德森
Do it!  Fire in the hole!
动手 开火
我们赶快离开这里吧
Okay, great.  Let's get the hell  outta here!
我们要封锁这个区域
We're sealing the tunnel.  Come on, baby.
快点
[ Welder Crackling ]
希望有用
For what it's worth.
我要你戴上这个
Here. I want you  to put this on.
做什么？
- What's it for?  - It's a locator.
定位器
Then I can find you  anywhere in the complex  on this.
可以在任何地方找到你
[ Beeping ]
只是为安全起见
It's just  a precaution.  Thanks.
谢了
这不表示我们订婚了
Doesn't mean we're  engaged or anything.
下一步是什么？
All right,  what's next?
[ Beeping ]
[ Door Closes ]
到了
Last stop.
上床
Get in.
脚放进去
Scoot down.  That's good.
这才乖，在这儿睡一下
Now, you lie here  and have a nap.  You're very tired.
你累坏了
我不睡，我会做恶梦
I don't want to.  I have scary dreams.
我打赌卡西不会做恶梦
Well, I bet Casey doesn't  have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
没有，没有什么
Nope. Nothing bad  in there.
看，你可以跟她一样
See? Maybe you could  just try to be like her, hmm?
蕾普莉，她是不会做恶梦的
Ripley, she doesn't  have bad dreams...
她只是布偶
because she's just  a piece of plastic.
对，抱歉，妞特
Right.  I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
我妈常说这里没有真的怪物
My mommy always said  there were no monsters-
可是真的有
no real ones-  but there are.
真的有
Yes, there are,  aren't there?
他们为什么这么说？
Why do they tell  little kids that?
多数时候他们都是对的
Most of the time  it's true.
她会不会被怪兽攻击
Did one of those things  grow inside her?
我不知道，真的
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
人类的小孩 不就是这样来的吗？
Isn't that how babies come?  I mean, people babies?
不，两者有很大的不同
They grow inside you.  Oh, that's very different.
你有没有生过小孩？
Did you ever  have a baby?
有
Yes, I did.  I had a little girl.
我有一个小女儿
她现在在哪里？
Where is she?  She's gone.
她走了
你是说她死了？
You mean dead.
这给你
Here.
来，戴上它
Take this.
保平安用
For luck.
好了
There's that.
别走，拜托
Don't go, please.
我就在隔壁
Newt, I'm gonna be  right in the next room.
看到墙上的电眼吗？
And you see that camera  right up there?
我从那里看到你是不是安全
I can see you  right through that camera,
all the time  to see if you're safe.
我不会离开你，妞特，真的
I'm not gonna  leave you, Newt.
I mean that.  That's a promise.
我保证
你保证？
You promise?
我发誓
I cross my heart.
死都不会
- And hope to die?  - And hope to die.
[ Kisses ]
睡吧
Now go to sleep,  and don't dream.
不要做梦
[ Laughs ]
小鬼
Sneak.
[ Door Opens ]
怪物死后酸血层氧化就没危险
The molecular acid oxidizes  after the creature's death,  completely neutralizing it.
很有意思，不过我没兴趣
Bishop, you know, that's  very interesting, but it doesn't  really get us anywhere, does it?
我们到底在对抗什么东西？
I'm trying to figure out  what we're dealing with here.
重新想想
Let's go through it again.
它们捉住移民再繁殖更多怪物
They grab the colonists,  they move them over there...
这表示有更多异形，对吗？
and they immobilize them  to be hosts for more of these.
Which would mean that  there would have to be  a lot of these parasites, right?
至少超过一百只
One for each colonist.  That's over 100, at least.
是的，没错
Yes. Τhat follows.
每个异形都是卵生的
But each one of these things  comes from an egg, right?
谁把蛋藏起来呢？
So who's laying  these eggs?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
一定是我们还没见过的东西
It must be something  we haven't seen yet.
也许就像蚂蚁窝
Hey, maybe it's like  an ant hive.
你是说蜂窝吧？
Bees, man.  Bees have hives.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.  There's, like, one female  that runs the whole show.
它就像是女王蜂一样掌控全局
没错，就是女王蜂
Yes, the queen.  Ueah, the mama.
没错，就是它，它很难缠
She's badass, man.  I mean, big.
这些东西可不像蚂蚁 我知道
These things ain't ants,  estúpido.  I know that.
我要你把标本销毁，懂吗？
Bishop, I want these specimens  destroyed as soon as  you're finished with them.
- Is that clear?  - Mr. Burke gave instructions...
巴克先生叫我带活标本回基地
that they were to be kept alive  in stasis for return  to the company labs.
他特别交待的
He was very specific  about it.
这些标本价值非凡
Look. Those two specimens  are worth millions  to the bio-weapons division, right?
如果你够聪明
Now, if you're smart,  we can both come out  of this heroes,
咱们会成为英雄
下半辈子都不愁吃穿
and we will be  set up for life.
你疯了，巴克，你知道吗？
You're crazy, Burke.  Do you know that?
这种危险生物能通过检疫吗？
Do you really think you can get  a dangerous organism like that  past I.C.C. quarantine?
没人了解它们，怎么通不过？
How can they impound it  if they don't  know about it?
我会告诉他们
But they will know about it,  Burke, from me.
他们也会知道 你害死157个移民
Just like they'll know  that you were responsible  for the deaths of 157 colonists.
等一下
Wait a second.  You sent them  to that ship.
你派他们来这里
You're wrong.  I just checked  the colony log.
你弄错了
我查过移民日志
出发日期61279 巴克卡特签署
Directive dated 6-1 2-79,  signed Burke, Carter J.
你派他们来，却没警告他们
You sent them out there,  and you didn't even warn them.
你为何不警告他们？
Why didn't you  warn them, Burke?  Okay, look.
听着
What if that ship  didn't even exist?  Do you ever think about that?
你想过那鬼船也许不存在吗？
我并不知道
I didn't know. So now  if I went and made a major  security situation out of it,
要是我小题大做
每个单位都来干涉
everybody steps in,  administration steps in, and  there's no exclusive rights for anybody.
公司得不到专利权大家都吃亏
Nobody wins.  So I made a decision,  and it was wrong.
我犯了错，我只是判断错误
It was a bad call, Ripley.  It was a bad call.
判断错误？那些人都死了
Bad call?  Right.
你知道你干了什么吗？
These people  are dead, Burke!
Don't you have any idea  what you've done here?
我一定要让他们逮到你
I'm gonna make sure  that they nail you  right to the wall for this!
别想夹着尾巴跑掉
You're not gonna  sleaze your way  out of this one.
我要整垮你
Right to the wall.
蕾普莉
Ripley. I-
我本来对你很有信心
You know, I expected  more from you.
我以为你是聪明人
I thought you'd be  smarter than this.
我很高兴让你失望
Well, I'm happy  to disappoint you.
[Alarm Blaring ]
怎么回事？
- [ Hudson ]  What is it? What's going on?  - They're coming.
它们来了 在哪里？
Where?  In the tunnel.
在坠道里
[Automatic Gunfire ]
Here we go. "A" and "B"  gun tracking far end.  Multiple targets.
我们的武器已经追踪到它们 并开火
目标有好多个
这些武器还真行
Those ammo counters go.
弹药已经用掉一半了
"B" gun's down 50%..
下面一定战况激烈
Man, it's a shooting gallery  down there.
B枪只剩下50发子弹了
- [ Hicks ]  Sixty rounds left on "B."  - [ Beeping ]
40发，20发，10发
Forty. Twenty. Ten.
B枪弹药已经用完了
"B" gun's dry.  Twenty on "A."
A枪只剩下20发
10发，5发
- Ten. Five.  - [ Steady Beep ]
用完了，老天啊
That's it.
下面真是一场混战
Jesus, they were  wall-to-wall in there.
[ Pounding ]
它们在撞门
They're at  the pressure door.
我的天啊
Man, listen to that.
我是毕夏，有坏消息
Bishop here.  I'm afraid I have  some bad news.
这倒新鲜
Well, that's a switch.
很漂亮，有什么问题
It's very pretty, Bishop,  but what are we looking for?
就是那个，紧急通风口
That's it.  Emergency venting.
真好
Oh, that's beautiful, man.  Oh, man, that-  that just beats it all.
多久喷一次？
How long till it blows?  Four hours.
还有多久
[ Groans ]  With a blast radius  of 30 kilometers,
范围大概30公里半径
平均4千万吨
equal to about  40 megatons.
难题来了
We got problems.  [ Hudson ] I don't believe this.  I don't fucking believe this.
我不敢相信
娃丝佳，把窗闸关起来
Vasquez,  close the shutters.
为什么不从这里关闭？
Why can't we shut it  down from here?
抱歉，坠机造成严重损害
I'm sorry.  The crash caused  too much damage.
没有办法修复
An overload is inevitable  at this point.
天，越来越没希望
Oh, man, and I was  getting short.
只差4星期我便可以退役
Four more weeks and out.  Now l'm gonna buy it  on this rock.
我们被困死了
It ain't half fair, man.  Hudson, give us a break!
哈德逊，少罗唆
[ Hudson ]  Four more weeks. Oh, man.
四个礼拜，天啊
我们必须派一艘船来救我们
We've got to get the other  drop ship from the Sulaco.
一定有办法摇控太空船
I mean, there must be some way  of bringing it down on remote.
怎么做？联络系统坏了
How? The transmitter  was on the A.P.C.  It's wasted.
不管怎样，我们最好想办法
I don't care how,  but we'd better think of something.  We'd better think of a way.
想个屁，我们死定了
Think of what?  We're fucked! We're doomed!  Shut up!
住嘴，住嘴
Shut up! What about  the colony transmitters?
殖民地的通讯器呢？
The uplink tower  down at the other end.  Why can't we use that?
不行，我查过
No, I checked.  The hardware in between here  and there was damaged.
那里的通道被堵住
没办法联接天线
We can't align the dish.
一定得有人拿电脑亲自去修复
Well, somebody's gonna  have to go out there,
take a portable terminal,  go out there  and patch in manually.
是呀，怪物就在附近
Oh, yeah, sure. With those  things running around?  You can count me out.
我可不去
你哪儿都不敢去
Guess we can just  count you out of everything.  I'll go.
没错，你去吧
[ Hudson ] That's right, man.  Why don't you go, man?
我去
[ Bishop ]  I'll go.  What?
什么？
I'll go. I mean,  I'm the only one qualified  to remote pilot the ship anyway.
我去
只有我有资格遥控太空船
应该让主教去
Yeah, right, man.  Bishop should go.  Good idea.
好主意
Believe me,  I'd prefer not to.
相信我，我宁可不去
虽然我是人造人，我可不笨
I may be synthetic,  but I'm not stupid.
有多远？
[ Ripley]  How long?
水管几乎一直通到上层大厅
This conduit runs almost  to the uplink assembly-  1 80 meters.
180公尺
爬到那儿要40分钟
Say 40 minutes  to crawl down there-  [ Ripley ] Right.
联接天线大约要一个小时
An hour to patch in  and align the antenna.
把太空船准备好要30分钟
Thirty minutes  to prep the ship,
飞行时间约50分钟
and about 50 minutes  flight time.  It's gonna be close.
时间紧迫
祝好运
Good luck.  See you soon.
回头见
小心
Watch your fingers.  [ Grunts ]
希望他顺利
Vaya con Dios, man.
真是不敢相信
This is unbelievable.  Twenty meters and closing.
你说这话什么意思？
有多少只？
Fifteen.  How many?
很难说，反正很多
[ Hicks ]  Can't tell. Lots.
D枪已经用了一半的子弹
"D" gun's down 50%..
[Aliens Screeching ]
C枪也差不多了
"C" gun's right behind it.
[ Hudson ]  Stopping them.  It ain't stopping them.
难道没有办法阻止它们吗？
D枪只剩下150发了
- [ Hicks ] 150 rounds on "D."  - [ Hudson ]  Come on. Come on, baby.
100发
[ Hicks ]  Hundred rounds.
加油
[ Hudson ]  Come on! Come on!
[ Beeping ]
B枪只剩下20发了
"D" gun's down to 20.
10发
Ten.
Damn it!
等等，它们撤退了
Wait! They're retreating.
我们的枪火阻止它们了
[ Ripley ]  The guns stopped them.
你说得对
You're right.
下一次就没这么多子弹了
Next time they walk  right up and knock.
不过它们不知道这点
Yeah, but they don't  know that.
它们也许会从别的地方进来
They're probably looking  for other ways to get in.
我们可以解决它们的
That'll take 'em a while.
也许它们被我们逼得动弹不得
Maybe we got 'em  demoralized.  Shut up!
闭嘴
我要你们在四处巡逻
I want you two  walking perimeter.
快去
Move!
听着
Hey, listen.
大家都快累死了
We're all  in strung-out shape,
可是要沉着机警点
but stay frosty  and alert.
那怪物进来我们就完了
We can't afford to let  one of those bastards in here.
好的
All right.  Vámonos.
你多久没睡？24小时？
How long's it been  since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
希克斯，我不想像他们那样
Hicks, I'm not  gonna end up  like those others.
你会“处理善后”吧？
You'll take care  of it, won't you?
如果那怪物进来
If it comes to that,  I'll do us both.
我会把我俩先杀了
听好，希望不会那样，好吗？
Listen, let's just make sure  it doesn't come to that.
All right?  All right.
我跟你介绍一个好朋友
Hey, I want to introduce you  to a personal friend of mine.
这是M41A电波机关枪
This is an M-41A  pulse rifle, 10 millimeter,
10厘米口径
with an over-and-under  30 millimeter  pump-action grenade launcher.
上下都有30厘米手榴弹筒
试试重量
Feel the weight.
好吧，我该怎么做？
Okay, what do I do?
抓紧
Okay, pull it in  tight here.  Right.
好
Uh-huh.  Lean into it.  Mm-hmm.
夹紧
会有后座力
All right.  Now, it will kick some.
当指数变零时
All right.  When the counter  reads zero here, you-
按这个？
I press this up?  That's right.
对
赶快换弹匣，用力卡住
Get another one in quick.  Slap it in hard.
这样就能大干了
Right.  And you're ready  to rock and roll.
这是什么？
What's this?  That's the grenade  launcher.
手榴弹筒，最好别碰
I don't think you  want to mess with that.
是你开的头，全教我吧
You started this.  Show me everything.
我能自己来
I can handle myself.
我注意到了
Yeah, I noticed.
你还好吧？
How do you feel?
还好吧！
All right, I guess.  One hell of a hangover.
好像大醉一场
蕾普莉，我只想…
Look, Ripley,  I just want-  Forget it.
算了，借过
Excuse me.
[ Newt Groaning ]
没事
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.  It's okay. It's okay.
“启动”
妞特
别出声
[ Whispering ]  Newt, wake up.
Wha-  Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
- No!  - [ Screams ]
Move, Newt!
[ Both Grunting ]
Hey!
[ No Audio ]
救命
Help! Help!
希克斯
Hicks!  Somebody!
主教，再说一次
[ Hicks ]  Say again, Bishop.
你接通自动加油的程式
You've got it  into auto-refuel mode,  and it's sequencing right?
频率没错？
好，继续联络
[ Bishop On Radio ]  That's right.  Okay, good. Stay on it.
等你发动引擎再联络
[ Indistinct ]  Get back to me when you've  activated the launch cycle.
他在上层塔台
太棒了
Roger.  He's at the uplink tower.
Good.  Terrific.
希克斯，希克斯，救命
[ Ripley ]  Hicks! Hicks! Hicks!  [ Newt ] Help!
希克斯，救命呀
- Help! Help!  - Hicks, help us!
把玻璃弄破
- Break the glass!  Break it. Break it.  - Yes.
弄破呀，弄破
我试试看
I'll try.
[ Scurrying ]
[ Clinking ]
我好怕
Ripley, I'm scared.
我也一样
Me too.
待在这里
Stay here.
[Alarm Blaring ]
是医疗化验室
It's the medlab. Hudson!
哈德逊，娃丝佳
Vasquez, meet me in medlab.  We got a fire.
到化验室会合，有火灾
马上来
[ Hudson On Radio ]  We're on our way.
他们来了
They're coming, Newt.
[ Screaming ]
- [ Grunts ]  - [ Screaming Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
射玻璃
Shoot it out!
哈德逊
- Hudson!  - Jesus.
[ Gasping ]
孩子，当心
Christ, kid, look out!
那边
Fucking die.
好了吗？
Over there! Ready?  Yeah! Yeah!
[ Hicks ]  Now!
哈德逊
Hudson?  Yeah. All clear.
安全了
Nailed the other one.  lt's history, man.  [ Coughing ]
另一只也死了，完蛋了
Jesus.
是巴克，都是巴克
Burke-  [ Coughs ]  It was Burke.
现在就宰了这混帐
I say we grease this rat-fuck  son of a bitch right now.
一点道理也没有
Just doesn't make  any goddamn sense.
他以为能偷运一只异形 通过检疫站
He figured that  he could get an alien  back through quarantine...
如果我们之中有人能…孕育它
if one of us  was impregnated-
不管你怎么说
whatever you call it-
然后把尸体冷冻运回去
and then frozen  for the trip home.
没人知道我们带着怪物回去
Nobody would know  about the embryos  we were carrying-
我和妞特
me and Newt.
等等，我们不知道
Wait a minute, now.  We'd all know.
他只要在回航途中破坏…
Yes. The only way  he could do it...
is if he sabotaged certain  freezers on the way home.
我们的冷冻库
Namely yours.
然后再把尸体丢掉 随便编什么故事
Then he could  jettison the bodies  and make up any story he liked.
他死定了
Fuck! He's dead.  You're dog meat, pal.
太岂有此理了
真是一派胡言
This is so nuts.
听你在说什么话
I mean, listen-  Listen to what you're saying.
都是你幻想的，真悲哀
It's paranoid delusion.
It's really sad.  It's pathetic.
真可怜
You know, Burke, I don't know  which species is worse.
巴克，我不知道谁比较坏
它们不会为了利益互相残杀
You don't see them  fucking each other over  for a goddamn percentage.
好，我们宰了他
All right.  We waste him. No offense.
不，他得回去
No! He's gotta go back-
它们把电力切断了
They cut the power.  What do you mean,  they cut the power?
什么？它们切断电源？
How could they cut the power, man?  They're animals.
怎么可能？他们是动物
你们去查走廊，快点
I want you two with trackers,  checking the corridors! Move!
高曼，看着巴克
[ Ripley ]  Gorman, watch Burke!  I got him.
交给我
Newt, stay close.
妞特，靠紧点
我走这边
I'll go this side.  You do that, man.
去吧
[ Tracker Clicking ]
有动静吗？
Anything?  [ Hudson ]  There's something.
那儿
[ Beeping ]  It's inside the complex.
它在里面
你测到的是我
You're just reading me.
不，不，不是你
No, no, it ain't you.
它们在里面，它们在这儿
They're inside-  inside the perimeter.  They're in here.
哈德逊，冷静点
[ Ripley ]  Hudson, stay cool!  Vasquez?
娃丝佳
[ Clicking ]
[ Beeping ]
哈德逊可能说对了
Hudson may be right.
你们都回来
Get back, both of you!  [ Hudson ]  The signal's weird.
信号好怪，一定是某种干扰
Must be some interference  or something.
到处都有讯号
There's movement  all over the place!
快回主控室
Get back to Operations.  It's game time.
开始吧
Newt.
妞特
把门封起来，快点
Seal the door.  Hurry!
快，快，回来
Come on! Come on!  Come on! Get back!
动作快点
Work fast.
把眼睛遮起来，别看火焰
Cover your eyes, Newt.  Don't look at the light.
有动静，信号清楚，20米
Movement. Signal's clean.
Range, 20 meters.
它们找到进来的路 我们有漏洞
They found a way in,  something we missed.
我们没有漏洞
We didn't miss anything.
18米…17米…
Eighteen.  Seventeen meters.
蓝图上没有的，我不知道
Something under the floor,  not in the plans.  I don't know.
15米，蕾普莉
- Fifteen meters.  - Ripley!
绝对在障碍物内
- Definitely inside  the barricades.  - Let's go.
我们走吧
就在门外，你们退后
Thirteen meters.  That's right  outside the door.
讯号真大
Hicks, Vasquez, get back!  This is a big fucking signal.
你那里如何？快回答
- How you doing, Vasquez?  Talk to me.  - Almost there.
快好了
好了
That's it.
12米
Twelve meters. Eleven.  [ High-pitched Beeping ]
11米
10米
- Ten.  - Then they're right on us.
他们要攻过来了
9米
- Nine meters.  - Remember- short,  controlled bursts.
记住，快速开枪
8米
Eight meters.
7米
Seven.
6米
- Six.  - It can't be.  That's inside the room.
在里面，不可能
上面这么显示
- It's reading right, man. Look!  - Well, you're not reading  it right.
你看错了
5米，兄弟们，4米
[ Hudson ]  Five meters, man.  Four. What the hell?
搞什么鬼？
[ Beeping Continues ]
老天，把灯给我
Oh, my God.  Oh, sh-  Give me the light.
它们来了，干掉它们
[ Shouting ]
There they go!  Over there! Get them!
- [ Aliens Shrieking ]  - Come on! Get them!
快，快，干掉它们
Do something, Gorman!
快想办法
[ Hudson ] Get them! Look out!  There's more of them!  There's more of them!
干掉它们，还有好多
Medical!  Get to Medical!  Do it! Now!
快到医药中心
快点
快
[ Hicks ]  Hudson, look out!  Look out!
[ Shouts, Screams ]  Now!
巴克
Burke!
Open this door!
把门打开，巴克，快打开
Burke! Open it!
[ Shouting ]
走
Go! Fall back!
去死吧
- Go!  - [ Shouting ]
- Die, motherfucker!  - Burke!
巴克
Hudson! Hudson!
哈德逊
王八蛋
Motherfucker! Come on!  Come on! Come and get it, baby!  Come on!
来，快点，过来
来呀，混帐
I don't got all day!  Come on! Come on!  Come on, you bastard!
你也一样，还要吗？ 你也想尝尝？
Come on! You too!  Oh, you want some of this?  [ Shrieking Continues ]
去你的
Fuck you!  [ Screams ]
Fuck you! Hicks!
希克斯
- Hudson!  - [ Screaming ]
哈德逊
[ Screaming Continues ]
快走
Come on.  Let's go!
锁住了
It's locked!
好了，走
- Got it! Let's go! Let's go!  - Go! Go!
高曼，快点
- Move, Gorman!  - Seal it!
封起来
巴克，天杀的，开门
Burke! Goddamn you!  Open this door!
[ Gasps ]
- [ Hissing ]  - [ Gasps ]
- [ Screams ]  - [ Hicks ]  Get back!
退后
- Hurry up.  - Gorman, get out of the way!
快点
高曼，让开
Ripley, this way!  What-
蕾普莉，这里
等一下，走在我后面
Wait. Get behind me.
我不管你要干嘛，快点
Whatever you're gonna do,  do it fast!
希克斯
Hicks!  Go!  Come on. Let's go.
走，快
Move!
降落场在哪边？
Which way is it to  the landing field from here?  This way.
这边
[Aliens Shrieking ]
向右
[ Newt ]  Go right.
这边
This way. This way.
哪边？
- Which way?  - Straight ahead and left.
往前然后左转
主教，听到吗？请回答
Bishop, do you read me?  Come in. Over.
船快到了，预定16分钟抵达
[ Bishop ]  The ship is on its way.
E.T.A., 16 minutes.
准备好，我们要去了
Stand by there.  We're on our way.
现在哪条路？
- Which way now?  - That way.
那条，不，这条
No, wait. This way.  You sure?
你确定吗？
娃丝佳，快来
Vasquez, move!
就在这上面
Right up here.  It's just up here.  Hicks!
我们快到了
We're almost there.
妞特，等一下，妞特
Newt, wait! Newt!
[ Shrieking ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Screams ]
娃丝佳
Vasquez!
走
- [ Grunting ]  - Go!
[ Groaning ]  Oh, no!
[ Pounding ]
妞特
Newt.
屋顶有捷径
Up there. There's a shortcut  across the roof.
希克斯
Hicks.
[ Clicking ]  [Aliens Hissing ]
高曼，你老是那么笨
You always were  an asshole, Gorman.
妞特
- [ Ripley Grunts ]  - [ Screaming ]
蕾普莉
- [ Ripley]  Newt! God!  - Ripley!
Newt!
希克斯，快去救她，快
Hicks! Hicks, get her!  Hurry!
[ Gasping ]
妞特，抓住
- Hold on, Newt!  - I'm slipping!
我要滑下去了
- Don't let go.  - Ripley!
别松手
蕾普莉
抓住了
- Hold on. Gotcha!  - Help!
我抓住你
- I gotcha.  - [ Fabric Tearing ]
- [ Screaming ]  - Newt!
妞特，不
[ Screaming Continues ]  No!
我们用这个找她
Come on.  We can find her with this.  [ Beeping ]
待在那儿别动
- Stay where you are, Newt.  - Ripley!
我们就到了
- We're coming.  - [ Beeping Continues ]
蕾普莉
Ripley!
这边
[ Beeping Speed Increases ]  This way.
接近了
She's close.  Newt!
妞特
蕾普莉
Ripley!
你在哪儿？听到吗？
Where are you?  Can you hear me?
妞特
Newt!  Here!
这边，我在这儿
I'm here!  Where?
妞特，你还好吗？
Newt, are you okay?
得切断它
[ Grunts ]  We'll have to cut it.
趴下，我们得切断它
Climb down, honey.  We've gotta cut through.
别动，要静静的
Newt?
Now, don't move.  Stay very still.
好
Okay.
快好了，你别动
We're almost there.  Hang in there, okay?
[ Beeping ]
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
希克斯，快
Hicks. Hurry.  I know.
我知道
I know!  I mean it!
我是说真的
[ Beeping Continues ]
妞特，你别动
Newt? Newt,  just stay still.
快好了
- [ Screams ]  - Almost there.
不
No!
妞特
Newt!
不
[ Grunts ]  No! No!
我们走吧
No! No! No!  Let's go.
它们不会杀死你
No! No!  They don't kill you!
它们不会杀她，她还活着
They- They don't kill you!  They-
她还活着
She's alive!  She's alive!
好，我相信你，她还活着
All right.  I believe you.  She's alive.
现在我们得走了
We've got to go. Now!
[ Ripley ]  Go!
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
- [ Screams ]  - [ Shrieking ]
快脱掉
[ Groaning ]  Get it off!  Hicks.
[ Groaning Continues ]  Get it off!
[ Coughing ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Groaning, Coughing  Continue ]  Here.
这儿
走
Go.
加油，你办得到
Come on.  You can make it.
[ Beeping ]
主教，还有多少时间？
Bishop, how much time?
很多，26分钟
Plenty.  Twenty-six minutes.
我们还不走
We're not leaving.  We're not?
是吗？
[ Beeping ]
别说了
Ripley-  I don't wanna hear about it, Bishop.  She's alive. There's still time.
蕾普莉
她还活着，还有时间
In 19 minutes, this area  is gonna be a cloud of vapor  the size of Nebraska.
再过19分钟这星球会化成烟
希克斯，别让他跑了
Hicks,  don't let him leave.  We ain't going anywhere.
我们那儿也不去
[ Beeping Continues ]
我们后会有期了，希克斯
See you, Hicks.  Dwayne.
杜恩，我叫杜恩
It's Dwayne.
我叫爱伦
Ellen.
爱伦，快去快回
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
[Alarm Blaring ]
注意，紧急情况，全体撤离
[ Computer Voice ]  Attention. Emergency.
All personnel  must evacuate immediately.
还剩15分钟逃至安全地区
You now have 15 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
注意，紧急情况，全体撤离
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel  must evacuate immediately.
还剩14分钟逃至安全地区
You now have 14 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Beeping Speed Increases ]
[ Rapid Beeping ]
[ Sobs ]  Oh.
[ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
蕾普莉
- Ripley! Ripley!  - Newt.
抱紧我
Grab on to me!  Hold on!
抓紧了
[ Hissing ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Screeching Stops ]
[ Screeching Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
我们走吧
Let's go!
后面
Behind us!
[Alarm Blaring ]
[ Screeching ]
[Alarm Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
注意，紧急情况，全体撤离
[ Computer Voice ]  Attention. Emergency.
All personnel  must evacuate immediately.
注意，紧急情况，全体撤离
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel  must evacuate immediately.
剩4分钟逃至安全地区
You now have four minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
[ Pounding Buttons ]  [ Screeching, Distant ]
快点呀，该死
Come on, goddamn it!
Hold on to me!
抱紧我
[ Hissing ]
[ Screeching ]
全体撤离
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel  must evacuate immediately.
剩2分钟逃至安全地区
You now have two minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
糟了
No.
主教，你真该死
Bishop, goddamn you!
宝贝，把眼睛闭上
Close your eyes, baby.
看
Look!
[ Screeching ]
快呀
Come on! Come on!
主教，全速前进
Punch it, Bishop!
[ Explosion ]
没事了，安全了
It's okay.  We're okay.
Hey.
我们成功了
We made it.
我就知道你会来
I knew you'd come.
他会复原，他只是昏过去
He's gonna be all right.  He's just out.
我给他打了一针
I had to give him another shot  for the pain.
我们需要担架送他就医
We need a stretcher  to carry him up to Medical.
好
Okay.
抱歉把你吓坏，起落站不稳定
I'm sorry if I scared you.  That platform wasjust  becoming too unstable.
我只好绕飞希望别出问题
I had to circle and hope  that things didn't get  too rough to take you off.
主教，你做的很好
Bishop, you did okay.
真的
- I did?  - Oh, yeah.
是的
[ Sizzling ]
[ Gasps ]
走，快走
不，这边
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
快跑
- [ Hissing ]  - Run!
这边
Here!
[ Pounding ]
[ Footsteps Clanging ]
- [ Hissing ]  - [ Yelps ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Door Rattling ]
离她远点，贱货
Get away from her,  you bitch!
[ Hisses ]
[ Screeches ]
- [ Shouts ]  - [ Screeching ]
- [ Hisses ]  - Come on! Come on!
[ Screeching ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Screaming ]
蕾普莉
Ripley!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Screaming ]  - [ Shouting ]
[ Shouting ]
- [ Screams ]  - [ Screeching ]
[ Screaming ]
主教
Bishop!
抱我
Mommy.  Oh, God!
天呀
你这人类算是不错
Not bad for a h-human.
我们是不是要一路睡到家？
Are we gonna sleep  all the way home?
对
All the way home.  Can I dream?
我能做梦吗？
当然，亲爱的，我俩都能做梦
Yes, honey.  I think we both can.
[ Chuckles ]
好好睡
Sleep tight.  Affirmative.
我同意
[ Scurrying ]
English - US - PSDH